TRAN HOAN DUC DUY

🔳 0888-193-215 🔀 ducduyleo@gmail.com 🤚 linkedin.com/in/hdduytran 🔘 github.com/hdduytran 🏔 duytran.id.vn

With a solid foundation in programming that began in my Informatics class during high school, coupled with one vear of professional experience in Software Development, I have developed a passion for data engineering. My goal is to be a technical expert and design systems that are highly concurrent and offer low latency, particularly in the era of big data. This unique combination of academic and professional experience positions me to make significant contributions in the field of data engineering.

Education

University of Information Technology (UIT) - VNUHCM

Jul 2022

Bachelor of Computer Science

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Technical Skills

• Python

• NoSQL/MongoDB

• Kafka/Spark

• Web Scraping

• SQL/MySQL

ElasticSearch

• AI/Tensorflow, Pytorch

Experience

Data Engineer

Hiip. Asia

Jua 2023 - Obt 2023 Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

• Developed ETL processes for data from various social media platforms (TikTok, Instagram, YouTube, Facebook), in conjunction with user creation data, resulting in a database with over 100 million records.

- Built APIs to serve collected/real-time (scraping) data for user in Vietnam, Thailand, Singapore, Philippines,...
- Implemented batch processing for machine learning to enhance efficiency and reduce cloud costs.
- Built System monitoring dashboards, BI dashboard and alerting system.

Deep Learning Research Assistant - Part time

Aug 2021 - Present

Academic Research Group

Vietnam & Denmark

- Team size: 2 professors, 6 scholars in mathematics and computer science
- Facilitating and participating in weekly seminars on Deep Learning and Mathematics with researchers in these fields.
- Conducting research and implementing Deep Learning models specifically designed for time series data.

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Jul 2022 - Nov 2022

Kyanon Digital

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

- Transitioning machine learning models into production-ready services.
- Designing and implementing databases and APIs for machine learning models.

Projects

Influencer Marketing Campaign Management

February 2023

- Team size: 6
- Tech stacks: Microservices, Python, AWS, MongoDB, ElasticSearch
- Responsibility: Data Crawler, ETL Pipeline, ElasticSearch Indexing

Influencer Quick Analytics

February 2023

- Team size: 5
- Tech stacks: Microservices, Python, AWS, MongoDB, ElasticSearch
- Responsibility: Create APIs to Serve Real time data, Logging and enrich database by scheduling interval times.
- Achievement: Making API faster 9-20%, Saving 30% cost.

Vietnamese Scence Text Recognition

February 2023

- Team size: 5
- Tech Stacks: Tensorflow, AbcNetv2, VietOCR, Label Studio
- Responsibilty: Built Dataset, Research and Fine-tune SOTA Models

Awards

- Top 5 Team at Vietnamese Scene Text Competition for Accuracy
- Bronze and Silver Medals in Informatics at 21st and 22nd Olympic 30/4, respectively.
- 3rd place in the Wecode competition.